export const MANAGEMENTINLIVINGA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A set criteria for measuring an item or activity are known as",
A: "values",
B: "goals",
C: "standards",
D: "needs",
answer: "C. standards",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Management in living is concerned with decisions individuals and families make as they go through life to",
A: "make ends meet",
B: "achieve their life goals",
C: "identify available resources",
D: "accomplish set goals",
answer: "B. achieve their life goals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The purpose of floor coverings in home furnishings include",
A: "provision of shade and comfort",
B: "protection of floor, providing privacy and reducing noise",
C: "protection of floor, adding beauty and reducing noise",
D: "removing dust from feet, provision of shade and warmth",
answer: "C. protection of floor, adding beauty and reducing noise",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A well planned kitchen",
A: "increases work efficiency",
B: "must have most labour saving equipment",
C: "allows children to play while mother works",
D: "increases the storage space",
answer: "A. increases work efficiency",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Chemicals in hard water",
A: "form scum with soap",
B: "blocks water pipes",
C: "saves fuel during cooking",
D: "corrodes water pipes",
answer: "A. form scum with soap",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. An adolescent’s sex drive is stimulated by",
A: "the adolescent being engaged in sexual activity",
B: "hormones produced during puberty",
C: "peer pressure and curiosity",
D: "curiosity and experimentation",
answer: "B. hormones produced during puberty",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. When a girl dates more than one boy at a time, they are engaged in",
A: "group dating",
B: "casual dating",
C: "random dating",
D: "steady dating",
answer: "C. random dating",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A sexually transmitted disease which is incurable is",
A: "genital herpes",
B: "gonorrhoea",
C: "syphilis",
D: "chlamydia",
answer: "A. genital herpes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The process of helping individuals become informed about their rights to product consumption is known as",
A: "formal education",
B: "vocational education",
C: "consumer education",
D: "informed education",
answer: "C. consumer education",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Many people get married basically to fulfil their",
A: "social needs",
B: "physiological need",
C: "parents wishes",
D: "religious obligation",
answer: "A. social needs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Money functioning as a measure of value enables us to",
A: "save or accumulate funds for goals",
B: "exchange goods and services easily",
C: "compare prices of different goods and services easily",
D: "make transfer in the form of donations and taxes easily",
answer: "C. compare prices of different goods and services easily",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A person with a body mass index of between 20-25 is considered",
A: "underweight",
B: "overweight",
C: "obese",
D: "normal",
answer: "D. normal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The most challenging stage in the development of an individual is the",
A: "adolescent stage",
B: "adult stage",
C: "infant stage",
D: "toddler stage",
answer: "A. adolescent stage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. To be able to use resources well, they must be",
A: "limited",
B: "scarce",
C: "manageable",
D: "exchangeable",
answer: "B. scarce",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Formula feeding is used by working mothers because it is",
A: "a good supplement to breast feeding",
B: "a fashionable thing to do",
C: "a common method of feeding",
D: "less troublesome for the mother",
answer: "D. less troublesome for the mother",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Social hazards faced by children who are engaged in child labour include:  \nI. teenage pregnancy  \nII. early marriage  \nIII. dropping out of school \nIV. indoctrination",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I, II and III only",
C: "I and IV only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "B. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Saving energy in management means",
A: "it can be used to do more work",
B: "the amount of work that can be done is reduced",
C: "it is kept and not used",
D: "it can be transferred to someone to use",
answer: "A. it can be used to do more work",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The body injury liability insurance provides coverage against",
A: "injuries to the insured",
B: "injuries to passengers and others",
C: "damage to the insured vehicle",
D: "damage to other vehicles",
answer: "B. injuries to passengers and others",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Cash loan from the bank which allows the customer to withdraw over and above what he/she has in account is",
A: "revolving credit",
B: "bank overdraft",
C: "banker’s draft",
D: "personal loan",
answer: "B. bank overdraft",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. One’s inability to use skills efficiently implies that the skill",
A: "is limited",
B: "is scarce",
C: "is adequate",
D: "has utility",
answer: "A. is limited",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Most frequently used items are best stored within",
A: "normal reach",
B: "maximum reach",
C: "medium reach",
D: "lowest reach",
answer: "A. normal reach",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The two main ways of acquiring a house are",
A: "building and buying",
B: "renting and owning",
C: "inheriting and buying",
D: "renting and building",
answer: "A. building and buying",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. One advantage of renting a house is that",
A: "remodelling is usually allowed",
B: "rental payment is an investment",
C: "major repairs are the owners responsibility",
D: "the landlord is responsible for keeping the house clean",
answer: "C. major repairs are the owners responsibility",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A detailed time plan which accounts strictly for the day is referred to as",
A: "clock-time plan",
B: "time log",
C: "time pie",
D: "fixed time plan",
answer: "B. time log",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. In sequencing activities, marketing done before meals are cooked best describes",
A: "dovetailing activities",
B: "interwoven activities",
C: "interdependent activities",
D: "overlapping activities",
answer: "D. overlapping activities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Medical doctors, pharmacist, teachers and architects are all",
A: "entrepreneurs",
B: "managers",
C: "professional workers",
D: "paraprofessionals",
answer: "C. professional workers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The two main classes of consumer agents are",
A: "sales agents and retailers",
B: "wholesalers and retailers",
C: "wholesalers and hawkers",
D: "retailer and distributers",
answer: "B. wholesalers and retailers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The reason why it is appropriate to choose cooler of curtains for a bedroom is that it",
A: "makes the room brighter",
B: "lowers the temperature in the room",
C: "gives a restful background",
D: "makes the room feel warm",
answer: "B. lowers the temperature in the room",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Natural ventilation can be achieved through the use of",
A: "chimney and fan extractor",
B: "perforated fancy blocks and fan",
C: "perforated fancy blocks and chimney",
D: "fan extractor and fan",
answer: "C. perforated fancy blocks and chimney",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The principle upon which the iceless refrigerator works is based on cooling by",
A: "evaporation",
B: "radiation",
C: "convection",
D: "conduction",
answer: "A. evaporation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Cessation of menstruation in an adolescent could be due to",
A: "menopause",
B: "pregnancy",
C: "abortion",
D: "andropause",
answer: "A. menopause",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The ability to recognize ones potential and capability best describes",
A: "esteem need",
B: "social need",
C: "self actualization need",
D: "safety need",
answer: "C. self actualization need",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Factors which influence management include",
A: "knowledge, events and experience",
B: "health, height and experience",
C: "weight, knowledge and events",
D: "experience, events and height",
answer: "A. knowledge, events and experience",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Intrinsic values include",
A: "freedom",
B: "good nutrition",
C: "rest",
D: "good exercise",
answer: "A. freedom",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Effective use of time involves",
A: "planning, implementing and controlling plans",
B: "planning, implementing and evaluating plans",
C: "assessing, planning and implementing plans",
D: "assessing, planning, implementing and evaluating plans",
answer: "D. assessing, planning, implementing and evaluating plans",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A housewife can save time by",
A: "writing down all the work to be done",
B: "shopping on daily basis",
C: "careful planning the work to be done",
D: "thinking of what is to be done",
answer: "C. careful planning the work to be done",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A loan taken from the bank to finance a house is called",
A: "overdraft",
B: "bond",
C: "mortgage",
D: "auto loan",
answer: "C. mortgage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. An important fact about decision making is that, it",
A: "occurs at all stages of management",
B: "occurs on the spur of the moment",
C: "identifies the problem to be solved",
D: "reduces assertiveness by individuals",
answer: "A. occurs at all stages of management",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Differences arising from conflicts in expectation between adults and the youth is described as",
A: "family conflicts",
B: "societal crisis",
C: "personality clashes",
D: "generation gap",
answer: "D. generation gap",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Engaging girls in prostitution for the parents economic gains best describes child",
A: "discrimination",
B: "deprivation",
C: "exploitation",
D: "neglect",
answer: "C. exploitation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Meningitis is",
A: "a water borne disease",
B: "an air-borne disease",
C: "a sexually transmitted disease",
D: "a food borne disease",
answer: "B. an air-borne disease",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Hot food should not be put into a refrigerator because it",
A: "overworks the compressor",
B: "makes the inside smell",
C: "prevents food from drying out",
D: "transfer flavour into other foods",
answer: "A. overworks the compressor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The main aim of protecting the environment is to",
A: "preserve vegetation",
B: "promote good health",
C: "improve upon its beauty",
D: "introduce orderliness",
answer: "B. promote good health",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Some of the ways good lighting is important in the home include:  \nI. it provides pleasant atmosphere  \nII. it makes for efficiency in work areas  \nIII. it promotes safety  \nIV. it prevents eye strain",
A: "I and II",
B: "I, II and III only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, II, III and IV",
answer: "D. I, II, III and IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Hard furnishings include,",
A: "book shelves",
B: "cushions",
C: "chairbacks",
D: "mattresses",
answer: "A. book shelves",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. To buy an item you have not planned to buy is",
A: "credit buying",
B: "spending spree",
C: "impulse buying",
D: "comparative shopping",
answer: "C. impulse buying",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A person who plans and works to achieve it is",
A: "a planner",
B: "a maker home",
C: "an organizer",
D: "a manager",
answer: "D. a manager",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. An informed consumer is a person who",
A: "buys goods and services",
B: "is well educated",
C: "spends money with satisfaction",
D: "shops around all the time",
answer: "C. spends money with satisfaction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Why do individuals and families need to make rational decisions in the use of resources?  \nI. Family needs many and are varied  \nII. Available resources are limited  \nIII. To ensure a meaningful and satisfying life  \nIV. To be able to sequence activities",
A: "I and III only",
B: "II and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, II, III and IV only",
answer: "D. I, II, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A legal document which transfers a house to a new owner is called",
A: "blue print",
B: "site plan",
C: "deed",
D: "title",
answer: "C. deed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. Two important considerations in furniture arrangement are",
A: "design and space",
B: "function and traffic",
C: "design and function",
D: "function and space",
answer: "D. function and space",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. The most appropriate description of housing is",
A: "four walls and a roof",
B: "a place where people live",
C: "an environment with people and amenities",
D: "an environment with schools and hospitals",
answer: "C. an environment with people and amenities",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. Assets possessed by individuals and used for achieving goals are known as",
A: "goods",
B: "resources",
C: "equipment",
D: "wealth",
answer: "B. resources",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. Two individuals may not achieve the same goal the same time because resources",
A: "change from time to time",
B: "vary in quantity and quality",
C: "are material possessions",
D: "a means to an end",
answer: "B. vary in quantity and quality",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. One of the decisions taken during the planning process is",
A: "comparing outputs",
B: "supervising activities",
C: "changing standards",
D: "clarifying goals",
answer: "D. clarifying goals",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. The type of credit that can be used for buying inexpensive consumable items is",
A: "service credit",
B: "instalment credit",
C: "revolving sales credit",
D: "hire purchase",
answer: "C. revolving sales credit",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. A mother infected with HIV can pass it to her baby through",
A: "breastfeeding",
B: "bathing baby",
C: "caressing baby",
D: "changing diapers",
answer: "A. breastfeeding",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. The implementation process involves",
A: "checking and adjusting",
B: "controlling and organizing",
C: "putting plans into action and controlling",
D: "putting plans into action and organizing",
answer: "C. putting plans into action and controlling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. By using a dark rug or carpet, vertical stripped curtains and light colour for ceiling, one may",
A: "decrease the apparent height of a room",
B: "increase the apparent height of a room",
C: "widen the apparent size of a room",
D: "reduce the apparent size of a room",
answer: "B. increase the apparent height of a room",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. Permitting children to drink alcohol constitute",
A: "social neglect",
B: "emotional neglect",
C: "educational neglect",
D: "physical neglect",
answer: "A. social neglect",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]